Guide to the Ray Lyman Wilbur Personal Papers SC0064B
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Introduction of Biography of President Harding by Cyril Clemen 1939
Man's Forward March 1939
Statement to Palo Alto Times 1939
The Drama League Can Influence the Films 1939
Human Hopes 1939
Greeting to Summer quarter faculty and students 1939
The Goals of Education in a Democracy 1939
Address at Opening Assembly, Stanford University 1939
Socialized Medicine-A Misnomer 1939
Remarks concerning a Symposium of "How can Hatred be Dissociated from the Church as it Affects the Jew" 1939
Comments for the Palo Alto Times in connection with the 50th anniversary of the first motion pictures 1939
Why We Are Especially Grateful this Thanksgiving for Freedom, Personal Liberty and the American Way of Life 1939
A Message to Americans of Japanese Ancestry 1939
Radio Talk in favor of Number 5 on Oil and Gas Control, Referendum of California Legislative Act 1939
Statement to the Palo Alto Times regarding Angell, Professor Frank 1939
Foreword to booklet on Pysiotherapy Therapy 1939
Guest Editorial for the Chinese Digest 1939
The Fore-Brain Behind 1939
China Has Much to Offer 1940
Foreword for book of selections from Epictetus by Sweet, Clytie 1940
Human Hopes—A Talk about the Family 1940
Health First 1940
Statement for Stanford Daily on Finnish Relief 1940
Interpretation of the Medical Profession by the Press 1940
Progress in Graduate Medical Education 1940
The University and the State 1940
Medical Care for the American People 1940
Resolution upon Retirement of Rockefeller, Jr., John D. as Chairman of the Rockefeller Foundation 1940
Biological Engineers 1940
Making Medical Care Available to the Average American 1940
Medical Care for the American People 1940
Establishing World Peace when the War Ends 1940
Remaking Historical Attitudes 1940
Personal Preparedness 1940
In Appreciation 1940
Mental Laundries 1940
Commencement Address at Palo Alto Union High School 1940
Wheels 1940
Talk to Graduating Classes 1940
Greetings to Summer Quarter faculty and students 1940
Review of The Patient as a Person by Robison, M.D., C. Canby 1940
Review of The Patient's Dilemma by Cabot, M.D., Hugh 1940
Medical Care for All 1940
Statement for editorial pages of New York Journal-American 1940
Address to Stanford Students 1940
Statehood for Hawaii 1940
Do We Change? 1940
Activities of the American Social Hygiene Association 1940
Applied Common Sense in National Defense 1940
Talk on "America's Town Meeting of the Air" radio program 1940
Greetings to New Students 1941
Foreword for We Pledged Allegiance 1941
Provisions for the Care of the Sick 1941
The Past Half century and Medical Education 1941
Article for Stanford Today 1941
The Beginning of a Journey of the British-American Ambulance 1941
Stanford's Next Twenty-Five Years 1941
Religion in the University 1941
Prevention-An Ounce Is Not Enough Today 1941
Universities in times of Strain 1941
Professional Education and Licensure 1941
Medicine in National Emergencies 1941
Some War Aspects in Medicine 1941
Statement on Student Extracurricular Activities 1941
The Vision of Our Founders 1941
Message for the Stanford Semi-Centennial Number of the Palo Alto Times 1941
Where Are We? 1941
Democracy and Commonsense 1941
Our Pacific Destiny 1941
A Statement on Selective Service 1941
Review of Plague on Us by Geddes Smith 1941
Statement on occasion of the 75th Anniversary of the National Board of Fire Underwriters 1941
Greetings for Stanford Student Handbook 1941
Foreword for the special 50th Anniversary Edition of the Stanford Daily 1941
Should the Community Party be outlawed in the United States? 1941
In Appreciation 1941
Milestones 1941
Stanford University 1941
Greetings to Summer Quarter Faculty and Students 1941
The Evolution of a Citizen 1941
Milestones 1941
You've Got the Biggest Job in the World 1941
Greetings to New Students 1941
Do You Think the Neutrality Act is consistent with America's interests, traditions and current policy? 1941
What is Before Us? 1941
Civics and Statecraft 1941
Remarks at University Assembly in commemoration of the opening of Stanford University 1941
Report on the Committee on Endowment Income to the Association of American Universities 1941
The Stanford Student and the War Crisis 1941
Stanford University 1941
Message to The Japanese American Courier 1942
Message for Stanford University War Bulletin No. 1 1942
American and the World Panorama 1942
Naval Aviation Recruitment Program 1942
Annual Report of the President of Stanford University 1942
Medical Care of the Civilian Population during War 1942
What Should We Teach Our Youth Now? 1942
Health and National Defense 1942
Chancellor's Column 1942
Grant, Joseph Donohoe 1942
What every American citizen should be doing now to help win the War 1942
Foreword to the Art of Falconry 1942
The California Physician's Service and the Low Income Patient 1942
Military Might 1942
Review of Rabies by Leslie T. Webster, M.D. 1942
Message for Cinema Forum 1942
Review of Society and Medical Progress by Stern, Bernhard 1942
Discourso Radial in La Revista Americana de Buenos Aires 1942
For Entering Students 1942
Short Wave Broadcast to Latin America in honor of the University of chile 1942
The University in War Time 1942
Stanford Today 1942
A Year Book of Public Health 1942
The Need for Technical Training 1942
Location and Movement of Physicians 1942
Chancellor's Column 1943
Review of The Furtherance of Medical Research, by Gregg, Dr. Alan 1943
A Volunteer Health Organization 1943
Report of the Council on Medical Education and Hospitals of the American Medical Association 1943
The Volunteer Spirit in Food Saving 1943
Stanford and the Army Training Program 1943
Baccalaureate Services 1943
Education in the United States after the War 1943
The Widening Geographical Horizon 1943
Foreword to Health Instruction Yearbook-1943 by Byrd, Oliver E. 1943
The American Plan of Postwar Germany 1943
Modern War and the Universities 1943
The Human Family, Inc 1943
A Mind Not Used Is A Mind Abused: A Message to Graduates 1943
The University President Essential Characteristics for Success 1943
The University's Part in Building the Citizenship of the World 1943
Storey, Thomas A. 1943
Better Health Care 1943
The Quality of Freedom 1943
Hoover, Lou Henry 1944
The Ware Department and Higher Education 1944
The Pacific: The Ocean of the Future 1944
Medical Education Today 1944
Stanford Traditions 1944
The University and the Machine 1944
Physical Medicine and the War 1944
Baruch's Gift to Physical Medicine 1944
Physical Medicine Gets a Boost 1944
Our Mutual Hemispheric Horizon 1944
Promiscuity as a Factor in the Spread of Venereal Disease 1944
Christmas Message to Stanford medical faculty and alumni in armed forces 1944
Statement on the Mayo Memorial 1944
Report of the Chairman of the Council on Medical Education and Hospitals 1945
Medical Service in California 1945
Statement on death of Roosevelt, Franklin Delano for Stanford Daily 1945
An Open Letter to the President of the United States 1945
Social Hygiene in Relation to the Future of the Family 1945
Guest Editorial for Pass in Review 1945
Stanford University 1945
China in America 1946
The Development and Protection of High Educational Standards by the Medical Profession 1946
La Fuerza de la familia es la fuerza del mundo 1946
Foreword to Who's Who in Latin America 1946
Memorandum of Conservation with Herbert Hoover 1947
Talk given at California Social Hygiene Association 1947
Foreword to booklet, "Responsibility of the Attorney General's Office in Venereal Disease Control" 1947
Foreword for Essentials of Public Health by Shephard, Dr. William P. 1947
Review of Mr. Jory by Hall, Wilbur 1947
Statement on Compulsory Military Training 1947
Review of California in our Times (1900-1940) by Glass, Robert, Cleland 1947
Should Men Marry Early 1948
My Faith 1948
Tresidder, Donald Bertrand 1948
Appreciation of Addis, Thomas 1948
Gardner, David Charles 1949
Rowell, Chester Harvey 1949
Prohibition -- United States.; Vivisection.; Environmentalism -- California.; Scrapbooks; Speeches.; Civil defense -- California.; Photoprints.; World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1914-1918.; Hoover, Herbert; Motion Picture Research Council.; California College in China.; Wilbur, Marguerite Blake.; Wilbur family.; Swain, Robert E. (Robert Eccles); Association of American Universities.; Hopkins, Timothy; California State Park Commission.; Golden Gate International Exposition. (Location of Meeting--San Francisco, Calif.); Data of meeeting of treaty signing--(1939-1940); Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Ely, Northcutt; Commonwealth Club of California; Wilbur, Ray L. (Ray Lyman); Sierra Club
- Personal papers, Bulk, 1875-1949 1829-1949; bulk; Series 1
  - Academie Diplomatique International (Box 1)
  - Adams, Bristow (Box 1)
  - Adams, Charles Francis (Box 1)
  - Adams, Prof. Ephraim Douglas (Box 1)
  - Alabama, University of (Box 1)
  - Albright, Horace M. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Ben Shannon (Box 1)
  - Alsberg, Dr. Carl Lucas (Box 1)
  - American Association (misc) (Box 1)
  - American Association for Adv. of Science (Box 1)
  - American Association of Junior Colleges (Box 1)
  - America, American (Box 2)
  - American Chemical Society (Box 2)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 2)
  - American Committee for Fair Play in China (Box 2)
  - American Council on Education (Box 2)
  - American Economic Foundation (Box 2)
  - American Library Association (Box 2)
  - American Principles and Fair Play, Pacific Coast Committee on (Box 2)
  - American Provident Society, Inc (Box 2)
  - American School for Girls-Damascus (Box 3)
  - American Society of the French Legion of Honor, Inc (Box 3)
  - American University Union in Europe (Box 3)
  - Anderson, Frank B. (Box 3)
  - Angell, James Rowland (Box 3)
  - Anthony, Charles C. (Box 3)
  - Appleton - Century Co. (Box 3)
  - Applications for positions (Box 3)
  - Architectural forum (Box 3)
  - Arden, Elizabeth (Mrs. Elizabeth Nightingale Graham) (Box 3)
  - Argonaut, the (Box 3)
  - Arnold, Julean (Herbert) (Box 3)
  - Arnold, Ralph (Box 3)
  - Associated Press (Box 3)
  - Associations (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1917-1918 (Box 3)
  - Association of American Colleges, 1917-1918 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities, 1917-1949 (Box 4)
  - Atlanta University (Box 4)
  - Atlantic Monthly (Box 4)
  - B, (BL-BO) (Box 4)
  - B, BR-BZ) (Box 5)
  - Baker, Shirley (Box 5)
  - Baldwin, Alexander R. (Box 5)
  - Ball, Katherine M. (Box 5)
  - Ballentine, Arthur A. (Box 5)
  - Bannister, L. Ward (Box 5)
  - Barclay, Professor Thomas Gwain (Box 5)
  - Barker, Robert A. (Box 5)
  - Barnard, Harry Everett (Box 5)
  - Barnes, Julius H. (Box 5)
  - Barrett, Richard W. (Box 5)
  - Barrows, David Prescott (Box 5)
  - Bascom, Mrs. Rose Upton (Box 5)
  - Bassett, Lee Emerson (Box 5)
  - Batchelder, Mrs. Francis Joseph (Box 5)
  - Batchelder, George Aiken (Box 5)
  - Baum, Frank George (Box 5)
  - Bauman, Frank A., Jr. (Box 5)
  - Beard, Charles A. (& Mary) (Box 5)
  - Becking, Lawrence G.M. (Box 5)
  - Bender, Albert M. (Box 5)
  - Bentley, R. L. (Box 5)
  - Berry, Fred L. (Box 5)
  - Birds (Box 5)
  - Bishop, Brent Fund, The (Box 5)
  - Blaine, Anita (Mrs. Emmons) (Box 5)
  - Bledsoe, Benjamen F. (Box 5)
  - Blichfeldt, H. F. (Box 5)
  - Bliven, Bruce (Box 5)
  - Bohemian Club, 1917-1943 (Box 6)
  - Bohemian Club, 1944 (Box 6)
  - Bolton, Frances Paine (Box 6)
  - Bonner, Frank E. (Box 6)
  - Book of the Month Club and Literary Guild (Box 6)
  - Booksks, etc. (Box 6)
  - Boomer, Lucius M. (Box 6)
  - Borax (Box 6)
  - Bourn, William D. (Box 7)
  - Bowman, Isaiah (Box 7)
  - Bradford, Harriet (Box 7)
  - Bradley, Christopher Mason (Box 7)
  - Brandin, Alf (Box 7)
  - Brandt, Karl (Box 7)
  - deBretteville, Mrs. and Mr. Alexander (Box 7)
  - Brien, Alfred (Box 7)
  - Britannica, The Encyclopedia (Box 7)
  - Brookings Institution (Box 7)
  - Brown, Everett Somerville (Box 7)
  - Brown, Harold Chapman (Box 7)
  - Brown, Hugh Henry (Box 7)
  - Brown, W. Sterry (Box 7)
  - Brown, Walter F (postmaster general) (Box 7)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (also, Institute of Pol. Relations files, China; East and West Association United; China Relief Institute) (Box 7)
  - Buckalow, Frank Russell (Box 7)
  - Buffalo, University of (Box 7)
  - Bunn, John William (Box 7)
  - Burbank, Luther (Box 7)
  - Burbank Foundation, Luther (campaign for farm) (Box 8)
  - Burley, Ebert K. (Box 8)
  - Bush, George B. (Box 8)
  - Bush, Vannevar (Box 8)
  - Byrnes, James F. (Box 8)
  - Coa-Com (general files) (Box 8)
  - Caldwell, Robert J (Box 9)
  - Calendar Simplification (Box 9)
  - California (misc organizations) (Box 9)
  - California Academy of Sciences (Box 9)
  - California Association for Adult Education (Box 9)
  - California Chamber of Commerce (Box 9)
  - California College in China, #1, 1931-1934 (Box 9)
  - California College in China, #2, 1935 (Box 9)
  - California College in China, #3, 1936-1937 (Box 10)
  - California College in China, #4, 1938-1941 (Box 10)
  - California Conference on City Planning (Box 10)
  - California Conservation Council (Box 10)
  - California Council of Education, California Teacher's Association (Box 10)
  - California Federation of Bus, and Professional Women's Club (Box 10)
  - California Folklore Society (Box 10)
  - California Forest Experiment Station (Box 10)
  - California Institute of Technology (Box 10)
  - California Labor School (Box 10)
  - California League of Women Voters (Box 10)
  - California Newspaper Publishers Association (Box 10)
  - California Pacific International Exposition (Box 10)
  - California Safety Council (Box 10)
  - California State Board of Education and Department of Education (Box 11)
  - California State Council of Defense (three folders) (Box 11)
  - California State Council of Defense (later War Council) (Box 12)
  - California State Council of Defense, 1942-1943 (Box 12)
  - California State Council of Defense (State Guard) (Box 12)
  - California State Parks (Box 12)
  - California State Park Commission (Box 12)
  - California State Park Commission, 1927 September-December (Box 12)
  - California State Park Commission, 1928 January-April (Box 12)
  - California State Park Commission, 1928 May-July (Box 13)
  - California State Park Commission, 1930 January (Box 13)
  - California State Park Commission (Box 13)
  - California State Reconstruction & Reemployment Commission (Box 13)
  - California State of, misc. (Box 13)
  - California Water Resources Association, California State Irrigation Association (Box 13)
  - California University of, Correspondence files, Before 1944 (Box 13)
  - California University of, & Presidents of (Box 13)
  - Cameron, George (Box 14)
  - Cammerer, Arno B. (Box 14)
  - Campbell, Robert W (Box 14)
  - Canfield, Mrs Helen Stanford (David) (Box 14)
  - Canning, John B. (Box 14)
  - Cantor Contest, The Eddie (Box 14)
  - CARE - Cooperation for American Remittances to Europe (Box 14)
  - Carlisle, Pearl (Box 14)
  - Carmel Institute of World Affairs (Box 14)
  - Carmichael, Oliver Cromwell (Box 14)
  - Carnegie Corporation (Box 14)
  - Carnegie Foundation for Adv of Teaching (Box 14)
  - Carnegie Institution of Washington (Box 14)
  - Carruth, William Herbert (Box 14)
  - Carskadon, Thomas R. (Box 14)
  - Carter, Joel Jackson (Box 14)
  - Carver Memorial Institute, the George Washington (Box 14)
  - Case, Paul J. (Box 14)
  - Cavalier, Mr. and Mrs. William (Box 14)
  - Century Association (Box 14)
  - Century Club (Box 14)
  - Century Company, The (Box 14)
  - Chan, Dr. Shau Wing (Box 14)
  - Chandler, Harry (Box 14)
  - Chapin, Leland Taylor (Box 14)
  - Chapin, Roy Dideman (Box 14)
  - Chapin, William Wallace (Argonaut) (Box 14)
  - Chicago, University of (Box 14)
  - Checkering, Allen L. (Box 14)
  - China and Chinese (misc.) (Box 14)
  - Chuck. Wah (Box 14)
  - Chrysler Corporation (Pres. K.T. Keller) (Box 14)
  - Cincinnati, University of (Box 14)
  - Citizens Federal Research Bureau (Box 14)
  - Citizens Fire Prevention Commission (Box 14)
  - II National Committees C:i. Tax Fdno (Box 14)
  - Claggett, Strabo V. (Box 14)
  - Clark, Fred G. (see also American Economic Foundation) (Box 14)
  - Clark, George Archibald (Box 14)
  - Clark, George Thomas (Box 14)
  - Clauson, Arthur C., 1937-1949 (Box 14)
  - Cleveland, Newton (and Mrs. Agnes Morely Cleveland) (Box 15)
  - Cleveland, Norman (Box 15)
  - Clemens, Cyril (Box 15)
  - Clubs - various (Box 15)
  - Cobb, Irwin S. (Box 15)
  - Coe, George C. (Box 15)
  - Coester, Alfred (Box 15)
  - Coffin, James G. (Box 15)
  - Cogswell, Elinor V. (see also Palo Alto Times) (Box 15)
  - Colby, Everett (Box 15)
  - Colcord, Samuel (Box 15)
  - College of the Pacific (Box 15)
  - Collins, Rose A. (Box 15)
  - Columbia Foundation (Box 15)
  - Columbia University (Box 15)
  - Commercial & Financial Chronicle (Box 15)
  - Committee on Cultural Relations with Latin America (Box 15)
  - Committee to Defend America by Aiding the Allies (Box 15)
  - Committee for Equality in Neutralization (Box 15)
  - Committee on Internal Exchange of Persons; Conference Board of Associated Research Councils (Box 15)
  - Commonwealth Club of California - Public Health Section Material (Box 15)
  - Commonwealth Club of California - Public Health Section Material, 1917-1929 (Box 16)
  - Commonwealth Club of California - Public Health Section Material, 1929-1948 (Box 17)
  - Commonwealth Fund, The (Box 17)
  - Communism (Box 17)
  - Community Chests and Councils (Box 17)
  - Comstock, Sara (Box 17)
  - Community Center at Work (Box 17)
  - Condolences, letters of, 1929-1933 (Box 18)
  - Condolences, letters of, 1935-1938 (Box 18)
  - Condolences, letters of, 1939-1942 (Box 18)
  - Condolences, letters of, 1943-1949 (Box 18)
  - Conant, James Bryant (Box 18)
  - Conference Board (Box 18)
  - Conscription, Peace Time Compulsory (Box 18)
  - Considine, John W., Jr. (Box 18)
  - Constitution Society (Box 18)
  - Cook, Philos (Box 18)
  - Coolidge, Calvin (Box 18)
  - Cooper, William John (Box 18)
  - Corcoran Gallery of Art (Box 18)
  - Cornell University (Box 18)
  - Cornish, Louis C (Box 18)
  - Coro Foundation (Box 18)
  - Coronet (Box 18)
  - Cosmos Club (Box 19)
  - Cottrell, Prof. Edwin Angell (Box 19)
  - Council Against Intolerance in America (Box 19)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (Box 19)
  - Council on National Defense (Box 19)
  - Cowling, Donald J. (Box 19)
  - Cox, Ross (Box 19)
  - Coyce, Albert F. (Box 19)
  - Craft, Marcia (Marcella) (Box 19)
  - Craig, A. V. (Box 19)
  - Craig, Hardin (Box 19)
  - Cram, Charles M. (Box 19)
  - Cramer, Stuart W (Box 19)
  - Crampton, Louis U. (Box 19)
  - Crane, Charles R. (Box 19)
  - Crary, Allen H. (Box 19)
  - Crocker, William W. (Box 19)
  - Crook, Wilton J. (Box 19)
  - Crothers, George Edward (Box 19)
  - Crowther, Samuel (Box 19)
  - Cruzan, Harold Ide (Mr. & Mrs.) (Box 19)
  - Culbertson, Ely (Box 19)
  - Cullingnan, J. S. (Box 19)
  - Culver, George Bliss (Box 19)
  - Current History (Box 19)
  - Curtis, Charles (v. p.) (Box 19)
  - Curtis, Lionel (Box 19)
  - Cutler, Leland W. (Box 20)
  - Cutting, Senator (Box 20)
  - Dafoe, John W. (Box 20)
  - Dakin, Mrs. Henry D. (Susan Davis Harter) (Box 20)
  - Dane, Albert E (Box 20)
  - Daniels, Arthur Hill (Box 20)
  - Daniels, Josephus (Box 20)
  - Dartmouth College (Box 20)
  - Daughters of the American Revolution (Box 20)
  - Davenport, Frederick N. (Box 20)
  - Daves, Delmer L. (Box 20)
  - Davidson, F. Trubee (Box 20)
  - Davis, Horace (Box 20)
  - Davis, James J. (Sec. of Labor) (Box 20)
  - Davis, Joseph Stancliffe (Box 20)
  - Davis, Mary Lee (Mrs. John Allen Davis) (Box 20)
  - Davis, Paul H. (Box 20)
  - Dawes, Gen. Charles Gates (Box 20)
  - Day Company, The John (Box 20)
  - Day, Mrs. Norman M. (Daisy) (Box 20)
  - Dean, Mrs. Luzerne (Box 21)
  - Deering, Frank P. (Box 21)
  - Delineator Magazine (Box 21)
  - Derman, Mrs. William (& Judge) (Box 21)
  - Denver, University of (Box 21)
  - Dickenson, Mrs. Velvalee (Box 21)
  - Dictionary of American History (Box 21)
  - Dimnet, Abe Ernest (Box 21)
  - Dinwiddie, Edwin C. (Box 21)
  - Disney, Walter E. (Box 21)
  - Disney, Wesley E. (Box 21)
  - Dixon, Joseph M. (Box 21)
  - Doak, William Nuckles (Box 21)
  - Dobbel, Charles A. (Box 21)
  - Dodds, John Wendell (Box 21)
  - Doherty, Henry L. (& Mrs.) (Box 21)
  - Dohrmann, Frederick W., Jr. (Box 21)
  - Dole, Charles S. (Box 21)
  - Dole, James D. (Box 21)
  - Dollar, Capt. Robert (Box 21)
  - Dolph, Cyrus A. (Box 21)
  - Donovan, William J. (Box 21)
  - Doubleday, Page & Company (later Doubleday, Doran & Company) (Box 21)
  - Downing, Paul N. (Box 21)
  - Doyle, Anastasia (Box 21)
  - Drury, Allen Stuart (Box 21)
  - Ducks (Unlimited) (Box 21)
  - Dudley, Ernest G. (Box 21)
  - Dulles, John Foster (Box 21)
  - Duncan, A. M. (Box 21)
  - Duniway, Clyde Augustus (& family) (Box 21)
  - DuBuy, William A. (& Mrs.) (Box 21)
  - Durand, W. F. (Box 21)
  - Durant, William C. (Box 21)
  - Dutton & Company, E. P. (Box 21)
  - Duveneck, Frank B. (Mrs. Josephine W.) (Box 21)
  - Dyer, Hector M. (Box 21)
  - Dykstra, Clarence A. (Box 21)
  - Earhart, Amelia (Box 21)
  - Eastman, George (Box 21)
  - Easton, Mrs. Ansel M. (Box 21)
  - Edgar, William O. (Box 21)
  - Edison, Thomas A. (Box 21)
  - Education - general (Box 21)
  - Edwards, Gordon (Box 22)
  - Edwards, Paul C. (Stanford Fund) (Box 22)
  - Eells, Charles P. (Box 22)
  - Einstein, Albert (Box 22)
  - Einsenhower, Dwight D. (Box 22)
  - Elder, Paul (Box 22)
  - Elkins, Felton (Box 22)
  - Elkins, Mrs. K. F. (Box 22)
  - Ellenwood, Frank O. (Box 22)
  - Ellerly, Nathaniel B. (Box 22)
  - Elliott, Orin Leslie (Box 22)
  - Ellis, William T. (Box 22)
  - Ely, Northcutt #1, 1929-1941 (Box 22)
  - Ely, Northcutt #2, 1942-1949 (Box 22)
  - Embree, Edwin Rogers (Box 23)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica, see Britannica, Encyclopedia (Box 23)
  - England (Box 23)
  - English Speaking Union (Box 23)
  - Equitable Life Assurance Society (Box 23)
  - Erwin, Ernest (Box 23)
  - Esbery, Milton H. (Box 23)
  - Espinosa, Aurelio Macedonia (Box 23)
  - Euphronia Debating Society (Box 23)
  - Eurich, Alvin Christian (Box 23)
  - Evermann, Barton Warren (Box 23)
  - Everywoman Magazine (Box 23)
  - Fairbanks, Avard (Box 23)
  - Falk Foundation, the Maurice & Laura (Box 23)
  - Family Farm, The (club) (Box 23)
  - Family Relations (Box 24)
  - Family Relations Center (Box 24)
  - Farm Journal & Farmer's Life (Box 24)
  - Farmer, Fyke (Box 24)
  - Farrand, George E. (Box 24)
  - Farrand, Max (Box 24)
  - Farrer & Rinehart, Inc. (Box 24)
  - Farrington, Wallace R. (& Mrs.) (Box 24)
  - Fast, Lisette E. (Box 24)
  - Faust, Pauline (Box 24)
  - Faville, David Ernest (Box 24)
  - Federal Council of Churches of Christ in America (Box 24)
  - Fejos, Paul (Box 24)
  - Felton, Mrs. Charles N. (Cora Smedberg) (Box 24)
  - Fickert, Charles E. (Box 24)
  - Fidac Jury of Award (Box 24)
  - Field, Charles K. (Box 24)
  - Fifield, James William, Jr. (Rev.) (Box 24)
  - Filene, Edward A. (Box 24)
  - Finley, Herbert (Box 24)
  - Finley, John Huston (Box 24)
  - Finney, Edward C. (Box 24)
  - Finnish Relief Fund (Box 24)
  - Fischer, Martin H. (Box 24)
  - Fischer Publishing Corp., L. B. (Box 24)
  - Fisher, Forrest Starkey (Box 24)
  - Fisher, Galen M. (Box 24)
  - Fisher, Harold B. (& Mrs.) (Box 24)
  - Fisher, Irving (Box 24)
  - Fishing [folder missing?] (Box 24)
  - Fitzhugh, William (Box 24)
  - Fleishhacker, Herbert (Box 24)
  - Fletcher, Senator Edward (Box 24)
  - Flexner, Dr. Abraham (Box 24)
  - Flugel, Felix (Box 24)
  - Ford, James ( & Mrs.) (Box 24)
  - Fordham University (Box 24)
  - Fordyce, E.L. (Box 24)
  - Foreign Countries (misc.) (Box 25)
  - Foreign Language Information Service (Box 25)
  - Foreign Born, Northern California Conference for Protection of the (Box 25)
  - Foreign Policy Association (Box 25)